hi I'm Brendan dress and I filmed this
video because I got an article posted on
strength coach comm I want to explain
some of the exercises so this is the
second video series the first was the
they are the supplying and bridging
progressions and this is the prone and
quadrant progression so make sure you
watch the first video of a series this
is a second and like I said all glute
exercise start off with a hip flexor
stretch you have to have flexible hip
flexors okay now the most basic front or
quadruped and glute activation exercise
are the quadruped a hip extension and
any bird dog so starts with these two
then how do we make these exercises more
challenging okay one way and I don't use
this one too often because the wave
sloshes around but some people like it
you can put a dumbbell back there just
kind of lean over and
so there's one method and then this is a
very advanced variation for the bird
dogs I just throw all ankle weights and
this exercise is really really
challenging kicks your putt but you
can't just start here you got to be good
so this one here I have 10 gone ain't
going to jump on dumbbells and come up
high and squeeze and hold it up
okay now we're going to move on to the
back extension now this one I got from
elite fitness and this might not be
practical for a lot of people - my legs
can fit through here so I do better leg
it back extension
it takes the hamstrings out of it mix it
mostly glue so kind of take some getting
used to getting in here but so now I can
perform better I get back extensions and
then when I want to apply weight I can
do that three different ways first leg
hold onto a dumbbell stay away ban also
do it one thing at a time when I do it
this way I don't use extra resistance I
just put my hands in the prisoner
so so those are the bent leg back
extension series are now I'm going to
show you what I do up the reverse hyper
so you want to be able to you know he's
got to be really strong until getting to
these exercises you don't just start off
here you got to really know how to use
your glutes but this is a bent leg
reverse hyper
now I can do this one leg at a time also
so and then the last exercise in this
series is what I call the pendulum
quadruped edge of extension and this is
right up there with the hip trust in
terms of good aggravation this here
people love this exercise this was a
favorite exercise almost every girl in
my gym who I train so you just have to
have a matter underneath and you scroll
under you got a back up
way back so now I'm wonder that and I'm
just gonna push upward
so
a lot of people say so that's not
functional you're using machine but I'll
explain some mins about functional
training and sports specific training in
another video but this was the second
video series first one was the supine
and bridging this one is the prone
quadrupeds series and next video is
going to be the abduction and external
rotation series so thank you